Finding Aid for the Bignou Gallery Albums, circa 1930s-1940s MS.24
The Frick Collection/Frick Art Reference Library Archives
Bignou Gallery Albums
circa 1930s-1940s
MS.24
The Frick Collection/Frick Art Reference Library Archives
10.0 Linear feet (33 Volumes)
Albums containing photographs and descriptions of artwork that passed through the hands of the Bignou Gallery (New York) during the 1930s and 1940s.
Bignou Gallery.
Derain, André, 1880-1954
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of 33 albums containing photographs of artwork that passed through the hands of the Bignou Gallery (New York) during the 1930s and 1940s. Many of the photographs are accompanied by information about the painting such as physical description, exhibition history, and provenance. The artists included are mainly French from the eighteenth through the twentieth centuries, and include such luminaries as Cézanne, Corot, Dufy, Matisse, and Renoir.
Access Restrictions
These records are open for research under the conditions of The Frick Collection/Frick Art Reference Library Archives access policy. Contact the Archives Department for further information at archives@frick.org.
Arrangement
Albums are arranged alphabetically by artist or movement.
Provenance
Gift of Carstairs Gallery through George Keller, July 23, 1962. Mr. Keller, then head of Carstairs, was formerly with both Barbazanges and Bignou Galleries.
Historical Note
Étienne Bignou (1891-1950) was a Parisian art dealer, noted for his paintings by artists such as Cézanne, Daumier, Corot, Degas, Renoir, Dérain, Picasso, Utrillo and Matisse. He opened his own gallery in 1927, and after Georges Petit's death, he purchased Petit's firm with dealers Gaston and Josse Bernheim-Jeune. Georges Keller was appointed director of the Galerie Georges Petit in 1929. After the gallery closed in 1933, Keller continued to work with Bignou at his Galerie Étienne Bignou and became the director for the New York branch of the Bignou Gallery in 1935. After Bignou's death in 1950, Keller closed the Bignou Gallery and became director of the Carstairs Gallery, New York.
Bignou Gallery.; Corot, Jean-Baptiste-Camille, 1796-1875.; Cézanne, Paul, 1839-1906.; Degas, Edgar, 1834-1917.; Dufy, Raoul, 1877-1953.; Lurçat, Jean, 1892-1966.; Matisse, Henri, 1869-1954.; Modigliani, Amedeo, 1884-1920.; Monet, Claude, 1840-1926.; Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973.; Renoir, Auguste, 1841-1919.; Rouault, Georges, 1871-1958.; Seurat, Georges, 1859-1891.; Toulouse-Lautrec, Henri de, 1864-1901.; Utrillo, Maurice, 1883-1955.; Art dealers--New York (State)--New York.; Art galleries, Commercial--New York (State)--New York.; Art, Modern--19th century; Art, Modern--20th century.; Impressionism (Art); Post-impressionism (Art)
- Album 1: Boudin, Fantin-Latour
  - Boudin, Eugène, 1824-1898
    - La Plage de Trouville en 1869, 1869
    - Port du Havre
    - La Meuse a Dordrecht, 1882
    - [Seascapes, beach scenes, ships, 31 paintings]
  - Fantin-Latour, Henri, 1836-1904
    - Roses, 1885
    - [Floral still life]
    - Fleurs et Fruits sur une Table, 1866
    - [Floral still life]
    - Asters dans un Vase, 1875
    - La Nappe Blanche, 1869
    - Les Marguerites
    - [Floral still lifes, two paintings]
    - Roses dans un Vase, 1885
    - Bouquet de Roses Blanches, 1872
    - [Floral still lifes, seven paintings]
    - Pommes, Assette, Couteau
    - [Fruit still lifes, five paintings]
    - La Feerie, 1863
    - [Three figures]
    - Portrait de William Ridley, 1867
    - La Musique, 1880
    - [Figures]
    - Nymphe Surprise
    - [Figures]
- Album 2: Cézanne, Paul, 1839-1906
  - [Landscapes, two paintings]
  - Les Sables Rouges, 1902
  - Matinée de Printemps a St. Anthonin, circa 1900-1906
  - L'Oree du Bois, circa 1882-1885
  - Bords de Riviére, circa 1900-1906
  - Tournant de Route a Auvers, circa 1879-1882
  - Ferme Normande, La Cour Plantee, circa 1885-1886
  - Paysage Provençal Aix-En-Provence, circa 1885-1887
  - La Montagne Sainte Victoire, 1899
  - La Montagne Sainte Victoire, circa 1897
  - Foret, circa 1882-1885
  - La Ferme du Jas de Bouffen, circa 1885-1887
  - Le Moulin a Huile, circa 1870-1871
  - Le Mur Blanc, circa 1871-1872
  - [Landscape]
  - La Montagne Saint Victoire, circa 1894-1900
  - Le Printemps, circa 1873-1879
  - Le Rocher Rouge, 1897
  - Paysage(Auvers sur Oise), circa 1885-1887
  - L'Eglise de Village, circa 1900-1904
  - Auvers sur Oise, circa 1878-1883
  - Le Matin en Provence, circa 1906
  - [Landscape]
  - Environs du Tholonet, circa 1900-1906
  - Bouquet D'Arbres, circa 1900
  - Paysage de Gardanne, circa 1885-1886
  - Le Jas de Bouffan, circa 1888-1900
  - Les Terres Rouges, circa 1885-1887
  - Cabane de Chasse en Provence, circa 1890-1894
  - Les Maisons dans les Dunes, circa 1878
  - La Maison de Zola a Medan, circa 1880
  - Le Mas Provençal, circa 1898
  - [Landscape]
  - Le Pilon du Roi, circa 1878-1883
  - Village Provençal a Travers les Arbres, circa 1890-1893
  - Le Jas de Bouffan, circa 1875-1876
  - Le Grand Chene, circa 1890-1894
  - Vue Prise du Jas de Bouffan, circa 1875-1878
  - La Carriere du Tholonet, circa 1897
  - Le Pont de Bois, circa 1898
  - L'Estaque, circa 1883-1886
  - Environs de Gardanne, 1885
  - L'Eglise de Village, circa 1865
  - L'Allee de Marines, 1896
  - Les Grands Arbres(Environs d'Aix), circa 1895-1898
  - Auvers sur Oise, circa 1879-1882
  - Genevilliers, circa 1879-1882
  - Ferme Normande: Le Clos, 1888
  - La Montagne Ste. Victoire
  - Les Chataignieres or Les Grands Arbres, circa 1895
  - Paysage Provencal
  - Les Chataignieres, circa 1890
- Album 3: Cézanne II
  - [Man embracing woman]
  - [Portrait of man]
  - Portrait du Pére de l'Artiste, 1875-1876
  - Portrait de Boyer, 1870-1871
  - Nymphes et Faunes, 1864-1868
  - [Leda and swan]
  - Jeune Fille à la Cage, 1888
  - Nymphes et Satyres, 1870
  - Self Portrait
  - Portrait de Madame Cezanne
  - Baigneuses, 1900-1904
  - L'Amour en Plâtre, 1895-1900
  - L'Amour en Plâtre, 1892-1900
  - [Portrait of woman]
  - Portrait de Jules Peyron, 1885-1887
  - Le Buveur, circa 1900
  - Portrait de Chouquet, circa 1885
  - La Baigneuse, circa 1873
  - Portrait d'Henri Gasquet, circa 1896-1897
  - Le Foreur, circa 1873-1875
  - La Tante Marie, 1867-1869
  - Portrait de Femme, circa 1892-1896
  - Portrait de Madame Cezanne, 1885-1887
  - Portrait de l'Artiste, 1885-1887
  - Femme Assise, circa 1885-1887
  - L'Homme a la Veste, circa 1875-1876
  - Quatre Baigneuses, circa 1879-1882
  - Les Grandes Baigneuses, 1897-1906
  - Le Jeune Homme au Petit Chapeau, circa 1885
  - Portrait du Fils de l'Artiste, 1894-1895
  - L'Enfant au Chapeau de Paille, 1896
  - Portrait d'Ambroise Vollard, 1899
  - Les Joueurs de Cartes, 1890-1892
  - Les Baigneuses, 1875-1876
  - Petit Nu, circa 1879-1882
  - La Preparation du Banquet, circa 1890
  - Les Moissonneurs, 1875-1876
  - Deux Baigneurs, circa 1866
  - Le Baigneur, 1879-1882
  - [Group of men]
  - Les Deux Enfants, circa 1857
  - Portrait de Madame Cezanne
  - L'Homme a la Pipe, circa 1890-1894
  - La Filette a la Poupee, 1900-1902
  - Pot de Fleurs - Géraniums, 1883-1887
  - Les Trois Cranes, circa 1900
  - Nature Morte a la Cruches, 1888-1890
  - Pommes, 1885-1887
  - La Bouteille Paillee, circa 1877
  - Nature Morte - Fruits et Enerier
  - [Apples]
  - Le Vase de Delft, circa 1873-1875
  - Grosses Pommes, circa 1890
  - [Apples]
  - Nature Morte
  - [Flowers in vase]
  - Crane et Livre
  - Nature Morte, circa 1895-1900
  - Pot Defleurs et Fruits, 1890-1894
  - Pommes, 1875-1880
  - Nature Morte, circa 1895-1900
  - Compotier de Fruits et Biscuits, circa 1877
  - Nature Morte, circa 1882
  - Fleurs dans un Vase, circa 1885
  - Le Vase de Jardin
  - Fleurs
  - Le Vase Vert, circa 1899
  - Fleurs dans un Vase, 1876
  - Fruits sur une Assiette, circa 1895-1900
  - Un Coin de l'Atelier de Cezanne, circa 1866
  - Nature Morte ├á la Draperie Bleu, 1885-1887
  - Nature Morte au Verre de Vin, circa 1882
  - Fruits et Assiette, circa 1890
  - Nature Morte au Tiroir Ouvert, circa 1883-1885
- Album 4: Corot, Jean-Baptiste-Camille, 1796-1875
  - Femme a la Mandoline, circa 1870
  - La Femme a la Mandoline, 1850-1855
  - La Blonde Gasconne, circa 1850
  - Portrait de Jeune Fille, 1850
  - Le Petite Jeannette, circa 1848
  - L'Italienne Agostina, 1866
  - Mademoiselle de Foudras, 1872
  - Melancolie
  - Judith, circa 1872-1874
  - Mademoiselle Leontine Desavary, 1872
  - Jeune Baigneuse
  - Jeune Italian Assis, circa 1826
  - Deux Jeunes Vacheres au Borde L'Eau, circa 1850-1855
  - Fillete Ecrivant, circa 1850-1860
  - Le Moine, circa 1855
  - Portrait de Leroux
  - Roses dans un Verre, 1874
  - La Ferme au Trois Comméres
  - [girl and farm]
  - Mortefontaine le Chemin a la Petite Barriere, circa 1850-1860
  - Route aux Abords D'Une Ville dans la Brie, 1875
  - Pre Borde de Saules, circa 1860-1865
  - Vue de la Foret de Fontainebleau, 1831-1834
  - Le Vieux Mont de Mantes, circa 1860-1865
  - Vieux Quais a Rouen, 1834
  - La Cathedrale de Mantes, circa 1860
  - Les Hauteurs de Meudon, circa 1872-1874
  - La Vieille Fileuse, 1849
  - Lac a Riva, 1834
  - Nemi - Le Lac vu a Travers les Arbres, circa 1834
  - Rochers Boises de la Serpentara
  - Piediluco
  - [sheep and herder]
  - Cour de Ferme, circa 1845
  - Ville D'Avray - Un Pecheur a la Ligne sur le Bord de L'Etang, 1853
  - Vue du Quai des Esclavons - Venise, 1834
  - Venise le Quai des Esclavons, 1834
  - Souvenir de Martigues, 1871
  - Un Voilier sur un Lac de Suisse, circa 1845-1855
  - [house]
  - Le Rivage, circa 1870
  - L'Etang aux Vaches, circa 1860
  - [landscape and figure]
  - L'Ecluse
  - Paysage Avec un Moulin a Vent
  - Le Manoir de Beaune la Rolande, circa 1850-1855
  - En Vue D'Un Port, circa 1860
  - Une Ferme de Dardagny, circa 1850-1860
  - Solitude au Bord de L'Eau, circa 1860
  - Etretat, La Ferme au Grand Chaume, circa 1872
  - Venise - Gondole sur le Grand Canal, 1834
  - La Chaumi├¿re des Dunes, 1865-1870
  - Ville D'Avray, 18665-1870
  - Moulin sur un Ruisseau
  - Palluel - Langues de Terre Plantees dans les Marais, 1874
  - L'Etang, circa 1855
- Album 5: Corot II
  - Les Saules, 1874
  - [portraits, 10 paintings]
  - [landscapes, 24 paintings]
- Album 6: Courbet, Daumier
  - Courbet, Gustave, 1819-1877
    - [portrait of Rembrandt]
    - Une Demoiselle au Bord de la Seine, 1856
    - La Femme au Chat Qui Pelote
    - Femme Peinte a Palavas, 1854
    - La Femme aux Gants
    - La Mere Gregoire
    - La Belle Irlandaise, 1866
    - Portrait de Femme, 1861
    - La Femme aux Deux Pigeons
    - [portrait of woman]
    - La Liseuse, 1872
    - Tete D'Enfant, 1865
    - Rochers au Bord de la Mer, circa 1866
    - Marine
    - Le Petite Cavalier, 1867
    - Le Chateau de Chillon
    - La Villa du Duc de Morny - Deauville 1869, 1869
    - La Plage a Maree Basse - Trouville, 1865
    - Marine Soleil Couchant
    - L'Orage sur la Mer
    - La Plage D'Etretat - Soliel Couchant
    - La Plage de Deauville, 1868
    - La Truite, 1872
    - Petites Fleurs
    - Pommes Citrons & Grenades, 1871
    - Fleurs dans un Panier, 1863
    - [portraits, 3 paintings]
    - Venus
    - Nu Couche vu de dans un Paysage
    - [portraits, 3 paintings]
    - Portrait de Tony Market
    - [portraits, 2 paintings]
    - [deer]
    - Biches dans la Neige
    - [ocean, 2 paintings]
  - Daumier, Honoré, 1808-1879
    - The Procurer, circa 1870
    - Les Deux Buveurs
    - Le Munier son Fils et L'Ane
    - La Serenade
    - Le Wagon de Troisieme Classe
    - Deplacement de Saltimbanques
    - La Rue
    - Conseils a un Jeune Artiste
    - Au Theatre Francais
    - La Laveuse du Quai D'Anjou
    - La Blanchisseuse du Quai D'Anjou
    - La Baignade
    - L'Artiste dans son Atelier
    - La Ronde
    - Don Quichotte dans la Montagne
    - Don Quichotte Rencontrant la Mule Morte
    - Don Quichotte et Sancho Panca
    - Deux Amateurs D'Estampes
    - La Sortie de L'Ecole
    - Medee Allaitant son Enfant
    - L'Atelier du Sculpteur
    - Au Theatre
    - Un Pientre
    - Tete de Sonneur
    - Deux Tetes de Juges
    - Le Depart du Train
    - Les Medecins
    - Le Boucher
    - Tete D'Expression
    - Le Violoniste
    - La Conversation
    - Un Juge
    - Deux Avocats
    - La Maman
    - La Veillee
    - Portrait d'un Inconnu
    - [2 paintings]
    - Les Lutteurs
    - [figure on a rope, 2 paintings]
- Album 7: Degas, Edgar, 1834-1917
  - L'Actrice Dans sa Loge, circa 1900
  - Jockeys sous la Pluie
  - Avant la Course, circa 1888
  - Avant la Danse, circa 1879
  - Portrait du Fr├¿re de L'Artiste, circa 1860
  - Le Joueur de Hautbois, 1885
  - Les Modistes, 1895
  - Jeune Femme Assise
  - Deux Danseuses
  - Portrait de Deigo Martelli, 1879
  - Mademoiselle Salie, 1886
  - Melancolie, circa 1868-1870
  - La Femme a L'Ombrelle, circa 1887
  - Head of a Woman, circa 1868
  - La Conversation
  - Deux Danseuses Serriere un Portant, circa 1895
  - Quatre Danseuses en Vert
  - Deux Danseuses, 1877
  - Danseuses Faisant des Pointes
  - Danseuse, circa 1884
  - [dancer]
  - Danseuse Entrant en Scene, circa 1880-1885
  - [dancer]
  - Trois Danseuses
  - L'Entree en Scene
  - Le Foyer de la Danse a L'Opera
  - La Repetition de Danse, 1878
  - [dancers]
  - Le Ballet, circa 1898
  - [dancers]
  - Le Faux Depart, 1872
  - Avant la Course
  - La Prairie, circa 1869
  - Etude de Ciel
  - Au Bord de la Mer
  - Quatre Danseuses
  - [horse and rider on ground]
  - [woman bathing]
  - Les Jockeys
  - [two women]
  - [dancer]
  - [jockeys and horses]
  - Plage a Maree Basse, 1869
  - Bateau a L'Entree du Port de Dives, 1892-1893
  - [jockeys and horses]
  - Le Jockey
  - [jockeys and horses]
  - [dancer]
  - [portraits, 2 paintings]
  - Femme Sortant du Bain
  - [dancers and portraits, 10 paintings]
  - La Coiffure, circa 1892-1895
  - [dancers and nudes, nine paintings]
  - Jockeys Avant la Course, circa 1878
  - Les Jockeys
  - Aux Courses: Le Depart, 1875
  - Portrait de Duranti, 1879
  - [man and woman]
  - Aux Courses, circa 1872
  - Danseuse Verte
- Album 8: Derain, André, 1880-1954
  - Jeune Homme au Chapeau Fendu
  - Le Modele Blond, 1923
  - Mademoiselle G..., 1919
  - Arlequin, 1919
  - [portrait]
  - Le Repos des Danseuses, 1927
  - [portrait of woman]
  - Jeune Fille Brune, 1927
  - [portrait of woman]
  - Tete de Jeune Femme, 1925
  - Le Chignon Noir, 1927
  - La Parisienne, 1926
  - Tete de Jeune Fille, 1925
  - [portrait]
  - [landscape]
  - Paysage du Midi, 1926
  - [landscape]
  - Le Mas
  - [landscapes, 2 paintings]
  - Grand nu Assis, circa 1921
  - [portrait of woman]
  - Femme Nue Etendue, 1926
  - [female nude]
  - Deux Danseuses, 1927
  - Le Repos des Danseuses, 1927
  - La Lecture, 1926
  - Le Vieux Pont
  - [still life]
  - Le Vase de Fleurs
  - Jeune Fille se Reposant
  - Fillette en Bleu
  - Tete de Jeune Fille, 1923
  - Portrait du Fils Bassiano, 1924
  - [portrait]
  - Le Jeune Homme au Chapeau, circa 1923
  - Portrait de Femme, 1925
  - [portraits, 4 paintings]
  - Portrait de Madame Renou, circa 1924
  - [portrait]
  - La Femme au Loop, 1927
  - Le Parlement et la Tamise, 1914
  - Somerset House
  - St. Paul's Cathedral, seen from the Thames
  - The Embankment, 1907
  - Barges on the Thames
  - London St. Paul's Cathedral, 1907
  - Le Phare de Gravelines, circa 1934
  - London, Houses of Parliament, 1907
  - Au Bal de Suresnes, 1903
  - [landscapes, 3 paintings]
  - Paysage, 1928
  - Paysage aux Environs de Bandol, 1926
  - [landscapes, 2 paintings]
  - Paysage en Provence, 1928
  - Paysage en Provence, 1927
  - [landscapes, 3 paintings]
  - Maisons au Bord de la Mer
  - [still life]
  - La Table Garnie, 1921
  - La Mappemonde, circa 1913
  - La Table Garnie, 1913
  - Les Poissons, 1924
  - Le Pichet Bleu, 1918
  - Nature Morte, 1918
  - [still life]
  - Pommes Poires et Raisins, 1927
  - Raisins et Pommes, 1924
  - Fleurs dans une Cruche, 1920
  - [flowers in vase, 2 paintings]
  - Le Bouquet, 1918
- Album 9: Dufy, Raoul, 1877-1953
  - [sailboats and houses, 4 paintings]
  - Les Régates à Deauville, 1934
  - Falaise, 1932
  - [sailboats]
  - La Baie de Nice, 1926
  - Golfe Juan, 1928
  - [houses and pier, 4 paintings]
  - Le Manoir du Vallon, 1935
  - Langres, 1933
  - Langres, 1933
  - [portraits, 2 paintings]
  - Portrait of Michel Bignou, 1933
  - Langres, 1933
  - Langres, 1933
  - [portrait of boy]
  - Deauville, 1933
  - Deauville, 1933
  - Deauville: Quatorze Juillet, 1933
  - Deauville: A Maree Descendante, 1933
  - Deauville, Après les Régates, 1933
  - Deauville, 1933
  - [people and horses]
  - Goodwood, 1931
  - Ascot, 1930
  - Deauville, 1931
  - Ensom, 1930
  - [sailboats and nudes, 3 paintings]
  - Reclining Nude, 1930
  - [portrait]
  - Grand nu fond Jaune
  - Rosetti, 1930
  - Deauville le Retour des Régates, 1930
  - [horses]
  - [nude]
  - Le Yacht Pavoise, 1930
  - [people on pier, 2 paintings]
  - [nudes, 2 paintings]
  - Les Deux Modeles, 1930
  - Deauville, Le Pilote de Regates, 1930
  - Vue de Vence
  - La Fontaine
  - Les Courses, L'Arrivee
  - Le Pesage
  - Jetee a Deauville, 1929
  - [pier]
  - [paris triptych]
  - [gate]
  - Nu Hindou, 1929
  - Nu Assis
  - Nu Assis
  - Nu Aux Arums, 1929
  - [people by the water]
  - Nice Promenade des Anglais
  - Nature Morte - Le Panier de Poires
  - Leda
  - L'Artiste et son Modele, 1929
  - Portrait de Madame Dufy, 1930
  - [street scene]
  - Ascot, 1931
  - Un Dimanche ├á Deauville, 1931
  - [river scene]
  - [sailboats]
- Album 10: Dufy II
  - Hommage à Claude Lorrain, circa 1929
  - [house]
  - Nice, 1927
  - Longchamps, 1925
  - [nine paintings]
  - Paris, 1934
  - Le Retour des Regates
  - Cowes, the Royal Yachting Club, 1934
  - [3 females]
  - Vence, 1938
  - [buildings and palm trees]
  - Joinville, 1938
  - Le Bateau du Havre, 1938
  - Le Bassin de Deauville, 1938
  - Nice, Fenetre sur la Promenade des Anglais, 1938
  - Nice, Le Guéridon, 1938
  - Nice, Le Balcon, 1938
  - Nice, 1938
  - La Naissance de Venus, 1938
  - Langres, La Moisson, 1938
  - Valabrice, circa 1927
  - [landscape]
  - Baigneuse a Sainte-Adresse, 1935
  - Cowes, The Royal Yachting Club, 1936
  - L'Atelier de l'Artiste, 1935
  - Nogent sur Marne, 1935
  - Nogent sur Marne, 1934
  - Le Manoir du Vallon[5 paintings]
  - Nice, 1932
  - Epsom, Le Défilé du Derby, 1930
  - [sailboats]
  - Grande Baigneuse a Sainte Adresse
  - Paris, 1934
  - Epsom, 1930
  - London, 1930, [3 paintings]
  - Landres - Le Parlement, 1930
  - Deauville, 1929
  - London, 1930
  - Deauville, 1939
  - Nu Couche, 1930
  - Epsom, 1930
  - [still life]
  - [horse track]
  - [nudes, 4 paintings]
  - [still life]
  - [sailboats]
  - Le Bassin a Deauville, 1929
  - [outdoor seating]
  - Le Jockey Sellant son Cheval, 1929
  - la Jetee de Honfleur, 1929
  - Les Courses a Deauville
  - Nu Debout, 1929
  - [nude]
- Album 11: Ecole 1830
  - Unknown
    - [portrait of man]
  - Barye, Antoine-Louis, 1796-1875
    - [tiger]
  - Boilly, Louis, 1761-1845
    - [fruit still life]
  - Carrière, Eugène, 1849-1906
    - [portrait of boy]
    - [mother and child]
    - Jean Dolent et sa Fille, 1888
    - Portrait de Felecien Champsaur
    - [portrait of woman]
    - [girl and dog]
    - [boy with hat]
    - [boy with lace collar]
    - [portrait of man]
    - [portrait of woman]
  - Daubigny, Charles François, 1817-1878
    - [landscape], 1874
    - [seascape], 1874
    - [seascape]
    - [seascape]
    - [pastoral], 1862
    - Rouen
  - Unknown
    - [crowd scene/procession]
  - Delacroix, Eugène, 1798-1863
    - Les Adieux de Romeo et Juliette, 1845
    - Desdemone Chassee par son Pere, 1839
    - Adam et Eve Chasses du Paradis, 1844
    - Chevaux a L'Abreuvoir, 1862
    - Daniel dans la Fosse aux Lions, 1853
    - [horse and rider]
    - Tigre et Serpent
    - Christophe Colomb au Couvent de Ste Marie de Robida, 1838
    - [horse, rider, other figure], 1856
    - Le Roi Jean
    - Josué Decamp
    - Le Christ en Croix, 1820
    - Vulcain
    - [man]
    - St Michel et le Dragon
  - Meissonier, Jean Louis Ernest, 1815-1891
    - Le Hallebardier, 1849
  - Henner, Jean-Jacques, 1829-1905
    - Jeune Fille Rousse
    - La Pensionnaire, 1873
  - Ingres, Jean-Auguste-Dominique, 1780-1867
    - Roger Delivrant Angelique
  - Unknown
    - [sheep]
  - Jongkind, Johan Barthold, 1819-1891
    - Clair de Lune sur le Canal, 1867
    - Rotterdam: Le Port aux Saumons, 1888
    - [ships]
    - [Rotterdam ships]
    - Port du Rotterdam
  - Unknown
    - [landscapes, 2 paintings]
  - Millet, Jean François, 1814-1875
    - Portrait Deleuze
    - [portrait of painter]
  - Monticelli, Adolphe, 1824-1886
    - Pastorale, 1851
    - Femmes dans un Parc
    - [home scene]
  - Puvis de Chavannes, Pierre, 1824-1898
    - Le Retour de L'Enfant Prodigue
    - Les Vendanges, 1865
    - L'Amphore Brisee
    - [9 paintings]
    - Mo├»se Frapant le Rocher
    - [4 paintings]
    - Dessin pour le Bois Sacré
  - Roybet, Ferdinand Victor Léon, 1840-1920
    - Le Mousquetaire, 1895
    - Les Adieux, 1894
  - Unknown
    - [3 paintings]
- Album 12: Impressionistes
  - Unknown
    - [landscape]
    - [woman and girl]
  - Cassatt, Mary, 1844-1926
    - Mere et Enfant, circa 1895
  - Jongkind, Johan Barthold, 1819-1891
    - Les Patineurs, 1878
  - Morisot, Berthe, 1841-1895
    - La Nourrice
    - [3 paintings]
    - Bord de Riviere
  - Pissarro, Camille, 1830-1903
    - Bords de Seine
    - Crystal Palace, 1871
    - Paysanne a la Fanchon
    - Coteau des Mathurins and Environs de Louveciennes
    - Vigne et Pommiers
    - Environs de Pontoise
    - [countryside]
    - Bedford Park, 1897
    - Charing Cross Bridge, 1890
    - Effet de Neige, 1874
    - L'Hermitage de Pontoise, 1867
    - [landscapes, 2 paintings]
    - L'Oise Prés de Créil, 1873
    - Pontoise, 1873
    - [countryside]
    - Bords d l'Oise, 1873
    - L'Arbre Mort, 1880
    - La Route sous la Pluie, 1870
    - Eragny L'Arbre Fleuri, 1888
    - [landscapes, 3 paintings]
    - Le Printemps a Eragny
    - [landscapes and portrait, 5 paintings]
    - Effet de Pluie and Pont de Moret
  - Sisley, Alfred, 1839-1899
    - [landscape]
    - Le Pont de Moret au Soliel Couchant, 1892
    - Rue à Moret sous la Pluie, circa 1878
    - Bords du Loing
    - En Normandie, Les Coteaux de la Buisse, 1894
    - [landscapes, 4 paintings]
    - La Route de Louveciennes, 1875
    - La Route à Marly, 1872
    - La Route de Verrieres, 1872
    - [city scenes, 2 paintings]
    - L'Inondation a Port Marly, 1876
    - Les Bateaux, circa 1874
    - Port Marly, 1876
    - [boats]
    - Le Pont de Moret, 1892
    - [landscape]
    - [landscapes and city scenes, 3 paintings]
    - La Ferme sous la Neige
    - La Seine a Argenteuil, 1877
    - La Seine a Argenteuil, 1877
    - Paysage D'Hiver, Effet de Neige, 1873
    - [sailboats and shore]
  - Rodin, Auguste, 1840-1917
    - L'Appel aux Armes
- Album 13: Impressionistes II
  - Unknown
    - [landscapes, 2 paintings]
    - [portraits, 2 paintings]
  - Pissarro, Camille, 1830-1903
    - [landscapes, 9 paintings]
    - Route de Melleray
    - L'Enfant au Tambour
    - [landscapes, 5 paintings]
    - L'Ermitage
    - Marche a Pontoise
    - [woman kneeling with basket]
    - Couple dans la Campagne
    - Gardeuse d'oies
    - [landscapes, 3 paintings]
  - Sisley, Alfred, 1839-1899
    - [landscape]
    - L'Automne, Le Matin, 1880
    - Bords du Loing
    - Hastings, 1897
    - [landscapes, 5 paintings]
    - Vue d'une Palaise
    - [river scenes, 2 paintings]
    - Maisons au Bord d'un Canal
    - [landscape]
    - Les Foundations a March
    - [landscapes, etc., 16 paintings]
- Album 14: Lurçat, Jean, 1892-1966
  - Baigneures, 1929
  - [2 paintings]
  - Paysage d'Afrique, 1933
  - [1 painting]
  - Pivoines au Bord de la Mer, 1936
  - Odalisque, 1926
  - Le Vase Bleu, 1936
  - [10 paintings]
  - Vision D'Espagne, 1938
  - [27 paintings]
- Album 15: Maitres Modernes
  - Bonnard, Pierre, 1867-1947
    - Paysage Classique, 1930